各位亲朋好友  今天大家齐聚一堂
Friends, family, we're gathered to celebrate here today...
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉缔结良缘
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
罗斯  请跟我复述
Now Ross, repeat after me.
我  罗斯
I, Ross.
娶你  艾蜜莉
Take thee, Emily.
娶你  瑞秋
Take thee, Rachel.
艾蜜莉
Emily.
是艾蜜莉
Heh. Emily.
要继续吗
Uh, shall I go on?
他说瑞秋  对不对
He said "Rachel", right?
我要站过去吗
Do you think I should go up there?
是的  请继续
Yes. Yes. Do go on.
我们最好重来吧
I think we'd better start again.
罗斯  请你跟着我说
Ross, repeat after me.
我  罗斯
I, Ross.
娶你  艾蜜莉
Take thee, Emily.
否则还会有谁
Ha, ha. Like there'd be anybody else.
成为我的合法妻子  无论贫病
As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
...till death parts us.
成为我的合法妻子  无论贫病
As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
...until death parts us.
真的  我愿意  艾蜜莉
Really, I do. Emily.
请给我婚戒
Do you have the rings?
艾蜜莉  为罗斯戴上戒指
Emily, place this ring on Ross' finger...
象征你永远爱他
...as a symbol of your bond everlasting.
罗斯  为艾蜜莉
Ross, place this ring...
戴上戒指  代表
...on Emily's hand as a symbol...
你俩白头偕老
...of the love that encircles you forever.
我很乐意
Happy to.
罗斯与艾蜜莉已经宣誓
Ross and Emily have made their declarations...
我很荣幸宣布  他们结为夫妻
...and it gives me great pleasure to declare them husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
这比他娶同性恋那次更糟糕
This is worse than when he married the lesbian.
保持微笑
Just keep smiling.
好
Okay...
进行得真顺利
Well, that went well. Yeah.
他没开枪杀死她就不错了
It could've been worse. He could've shot her.
刚刚真有点耍宝
Ha, ha. That was pretty funny, wasn't it?
老友记  第五季  第01集  阴错阳差
Friends  S05E01  The One After Ross Says Rachel
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
你搞砸所有事情  简直是恶梦一场
You spoiled everything. It's like a nightmare.
我的亲朋好友都在场  我以后拿什么脸见人
All my friends and family are out there. How can I face them?
你怎么做得出来
How could you do this to me?
罗斯和艾蜜莉  不管怎样
Hey, no matter what happens with Ross and Emily...
我们都吃得到蛋糕吧
...we still get cake, right?
没关系  亲爱的  你慢慢来
That's all right. No, no. You take your time, sweetie.
我在外面等你
I'll be out here. Ha, ha.
她要补妆
She's just fixing her makeup.
我恨你
I hate you.
我也爱你
And I love you.
罗斯  你偏挑这个时候  说错名字
Boy, a bad time to say the wrong name, huh, Ross?
你说得对  谢了  老爸
That's true. Thanks, Dad.
大家应该跳舞啊
People should be dancing, huh?
这是婚宴  来吧
Hey, this is a party. Come on.
乔伊  跳舞啊
Joey. Dance.
喂   华森室内设计
Yes, Waltham Interiors.
你好  我是罗斯盖勒的私人医生  费兰吉
Hello, this is Ross Geller's personal physician, Dr. Phalange.
谁
Who?
我发现罗斯忘了吃药
Yeah, I discovered that Ross forgot to take his brain medicine.
他这人不吃药
Um, now, without it, uh, in the brain of Ross...
就有可能讲错女人的名字
...uh, women's names are interchangeable.
这完全不能怪他
Through no fault of his own.
天啊  是菲比你啊
Oh, my God. Phoebe.
我不是菲比  是费兰吉医生
No, not Phoebe. Dr. Phalange.
你也错乱了
Oh, no. You have it too.
喂
Hello?
嘿  嗨
Hey. Hey.
希望你别误会
Wow, I hope you don't take this the wrong way...
我知道我们今晚约了要见面
...but I know we had plans to meet up tonight and...
但是我担心以后做不成朋友
Ugh. I'm just kind of worried about what it might do to our friendship.
我明白
I know.
我们怎么这么不小心  还不小心了七次
Ugh. How could we have let this happen? Seven times.
你知道  我们人在国外
You know, look. We were away.
又是浪漫的异乡  对
In a foreign, romantic country. Right.
都怪伦敦不好
I blame London.
坏伦敦
Bad London.
听着
So look, um...
既然我们还在伦敦  就可以继续  对不对
...while we're still in London, I mean, we can keep doing it, right?
看来我们别无选择
Well, I don't see that we have a choice.
但是一回家就不能做了
But when we're back home, we don't do it.
只能在这里
Only here.
我看到楼下有酒窖
You know, I saw a wine cellar downstairs.
我两分钟后下去找你  好
I'll meet you there in two minutes. Okay.
摩妮卡  我有事情要问你  现在啊
Mon? Mon, I got to ask you something. Now?
罗斯刚刚说出我的名字
Ross said my name up there. I mean, come on.
我不能假装没听到吧
I just can't pretend that didn't happen can I?
我不知道
I don't know.
摩妮卡  我该怎么办  做正确的事
Monica, what should I do? Just do the right thing.
什么
What?
听天由命  努力争取  不要死心眼
Tow the line. Thread the needle. Think outside the box.
等等  听着  我要问罗斯  他是什么意思
Monica, wait, listen. I'm gonna talk to Ross about what he thinks it meant.
等等  瑞秋  不行
Wait. Rachel, no.
他结婚了
He's married.
结婚了
Married.
要是你还不懂  我也没办法
If you don't realize that, I can't help you.
你说得对
Okay. You're right.
你说得对  你帮不了我
You're right. You can't help me.
杰克  这是我们的错吗  没把小孩教好
Jack, is it all our fault? Were we bad parents?
差不多吧
Yes.
没地方坐还叫人吃牛排
Oh yeah? Well, who serves steak when there's no place to sit?
你要我们怎么吃嘛
I mean, how are you supposed to eat this?
你们好  怎么样
Hey, what's up?
你去哪里了  不是约好了在酒窖碰面
Where were you? We were supposed to meet.
算了  当我没说  为什么
Forget it. That's off. Why?
两分钟后
The next tour of the wine cellar...
为各位介绍酒窖
...will commence in two minutes.
乔伊  你搞什么
Joey, what are you doing?
你答应菲比  等她生完孩子才吃肉的
You promised Phoebe you wouldn't eat meat until she has the babies!
既然我们在国外就不算
Well, I figured we're in another country, so it doesn't count.
那倒是  他说得对
That's true. The man's got a point.
嗨
Oh, hi.
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
抱歉  事情竟然出状况
I'm sorry things aren't working out so well.
的确不太妙  不过会解决的
Oh, no. Ha, ha. It could be better. It's gonna be okay, right?
当然  我的意思  她不会放在心上的
Oh, yeah. Of course. I mean, she's gonna get over this, you know?
你只不过脱口说出了我的名字
I mean, so you said my name.
不过是因为你刚好看到我
You know, you just said it because you saw me there.
如果你是看到怪胎  也会说
If you'd seen a circus freak, you would've said:
我娶你  怪胎
I take thee Circus Freak.
根本没有别的意思  只是无心之过
It didn't mean anything. It's just a mistake.
没有别的意思
It didn't mean anything.
对吧  不   不
Right? No, no.
当然没有别的意思
Of course it didn't mean anything.
但是我明白艾蜜莉为何误会
I mean, uh well, I can understand why Emily would think it meant something...
因为这刚好是你的名字
...you know, because it was you.
其实没有意义  真的没有  没有
But it absolutely didn't. It didn't! It didn't!
罗斯  乐队正在等你跟艾蜜莉来开舞
Ross, hey, the band's ready outside for your first dance with Emily,
乐队准备好了
Oh. Oh, the band's ready.
我们最好听乐队的话
Well, we got to do what the band says.
我才不在乎呢
I don't care about the stupid band!
你口水喷到我了
You spit on me, man.
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾蜜莉也进去太久了吧
Emily is taking kind of a long time, huh? Heh.
我结婚时也躲在厕所不出来
Y'know When I locked myself in the bathroom at my wedding...
不过那是因为我要撬开窗户
...it was because I was trying to pop the window out of the frame.
是啊  我心想着要逃出去
Right. Get the hell out of there. You know?
艾蜜莉
Emily.
我要进去了
I'm coming in.
你看  同一招
Oh, look at that. Same thing.
如果我中途
In the middle of everything...
大喊 "好啊"   你就当作没听到
...if I scream the word "yippee," just ignore me.
天啊  瑞秋  嗨  你好啊  瑞秋
Huh! Oh, my God. Rachel. Oh, hello, Rachel.
罗斯叫出我的名字
Ross said my name.
好吗  是我呀
Okay? My name.
他会说成我的名字
Ross said my name up there.
表示他还爱我
That obviously means that he still loves me.
不信就算了  我绝对没误会
Okay, don't believe me. I know I'm right.
你们要不要下楼喝一杯
do you guys want to go downstairs and get a drink?
好啊
Yes, we do.
不过我们要先换衣服
But we have to change first.
对  我想换衣服
Yes, I want to change.
你先下去占位子  我们五分钟就下去
why don't you go down and get us a table? Yeah, We'll be down in five minutes.
十五分钟吧
Fifteen minutes. Ha, ha.
哈罗
Hello.
菲比啊  是菲比
Oh, Pheebs. It's Phoebe.
嘿   太好了
Oh, hey, hey. Oh, great.
嗨
Hi.
怎么样
So, what happened?
罗斯说成我的名字
Well, Ross said my name.
我知道  不过他是无心的
Yeah, I know, but I don't think that means anything.
菲比  我们冷静客观想想看
Okay, Pheebs, y'know what, let's look at this objectively.
他从高三就暗恋我
All right, ninth grade, right?
从那时就疯狂迷上我
The obsession starts.
好吗  那年暑假
All right? Summer after ninth grade...
他头一次看我穿两件式泳装
...he sees me in a two-piece for the first time.
更是不可自拔地爱上了我  不是吗
His obsession begins to grow, right?
嗨  听着  去我房间换衣服好了
Hey, listen, why don't we go change in my room?
可是我的衣服在
My clothes are... Oh.
你看起来真是   没时间废话了
Wow, you look... No time for that.
好吧
Okay.
老兄  让我进去  我有女伴
Hey, dude. Let me in. I got a girl out here.
我这里也有
Well, I've got a girl in here.
才没有  我看到你跟摩妮卡进去
No, you don't. I just saw you go in there with Monica.
我们在里面聊天
Well, we're hanging out in here.
你说我们  谁比较有机会上床呢
Which one of us is gonna be having sex in there? Me or you?
看来我只能说是你了
Well, I suppose I would have to say you.
我们正在一起看电影呢  没错
What if we're watching a movie in here? Which we are.
我们付费了  正在看 "我的巨人"
And we've already paid for it. It's My Giant.
"我的巨人"   我超爱那部片
My Giant? I love that movie.
你确定这样好吗
You really think this is okay?
反正罗斯跟艾蜜莉也用不到
Well, Ross and Emily aren't gonna use it.
这里好漂亮
Oh, it's so beautiful.
可是我总觉得不太妥当
You know, I don't feel right about this.
摩妮卡
Oh, Monica...
这是蜜月套房
This is the honeymoon suite.
本来就该有人在这里嘿咻
The room expects sex.
如果没有  这间房一定很失望
The room would be disappointed if it didn't get sex.
在其他蜜月套房面前抬不起头
All the other honeymoon suites would think it was a loser.
好吧
Okay.
艾蜜莉  没有  这里也没看到
Emily? Nope. Not under here.
你还没找到她  没有  我到处都找不到
You didn't find her? No, I've looked everywhere.
你一定漏掉什么地方  否则早就找到了
Well, you couldn't have, or else you would've found her.
你应该继续找  大概再找个30分钟
I think you should keep looking. Yeah. For about, uh, 30 minutes?
或是45分钟
Or 45?
45分钟可以找到两次了
Wow, in 45 minutes, you could find her twice.
不了  她一定也找不到我
No. For all I know, she's trying to find me...
因为我跑来跑去
...but couldn't because I kept moving around.
从现在开始  我不跑了
No, from now on, I'm staying in one place.
我就待在这里
Right here.
时间晚了  我们要走了
It's getting late. Yeah, We're going to go.
这个
Actually...
在这里待一会儿如何
...do you guys mind staying here for a while?
可是我们明天一早  就要搭机回纽约
Ugh. You know, we got to get up early and catch that plane to New York.
而且那班飞机又很大
Yeah, it's a very large plane.
那就算了
That's cool.
不过我们还是陪你一会
But we'll stay here with you.
谢了
Thanks, guys. Ha, ha.
我很感激你们的好意  但是你也不用摸我屁股啊
I really appreciate this, you know, but you don't need to rub my butt.
我们一小时后就要回纽约了
We have to leave for New York in an hour.
我知道  我一直在看那扇门
I know. I've been looking at those doors.
隔音效果看起来很好  你觉得呢
They look pretty soundproof, don't you think?
不行  你疯了
We can't do that. That's insane.
第一  他可能醒来  第二
I mean, A, he could wake up. And B, you know...
管他的
...let's go for it.
艾蜜莉  艾蜜莉
Emily? Emily.
艾蜜莉  不是她
Emily! Nope.
不用找她了  她没跟来  我们来拿她的东西
Forget about Emily. She's not with us. We've come for her things.
她在哪里
Where is she?
她躲起来了  因为她很丢脸  这辈子都不想再见到你
She's in hiding. She's utterly humiliated. She doesn't want to see you ever again.
很遗憾你们两个闹成这样  兔崽子
We're very sad that it didn't work out between you and Emily, monkey.
不过我觉得你帅极了
But I think you're absolutely delicious.
抱歉  我人还站在这里
Excuse me, I'm standing right here.
是啊
Oh, yes.
阴魂不散
There you are.
大家动作快  外面还有一堆
Hey. Hey, you guys. Hurry up. Get some. There's a whole cart outside.
再见了  盖勒  等下  等下
Goodbye, Geller. Now, hold on. Hold on.
你女儿跟我
Look, look. Your daughter and I...
今晚预定去度蜜月
...are supposed to leave tonight for our honeymoon.
请你们转告她  我会去机场
Now, you tell her that I'm gonna be at that airport...
我希望她也会去
...and I hope that she'll be there too.
我是说成瑞秋的名字  但这只是无心之过
Yeah, I said Rachel's name, but it didn't mean anything.
她不过是我的朋友  就这样  请转告艾蜜莉我爱她
She's just a friend. That's all. Now, look, just tell Emily I love her...
我只想跟她共度余生
...and that I can't imagine spending my life with anyone else.
请保证  你们一定会转告她
Please, promise me that you'll tell her that.
好吧  我会告诉她
All right, I'll tell her.
走吧  臭婆娘
Come on, bugger face.
打电话给我
Call me.
你也一天到晚的待在厕所
You spend half your life in the bathroom.
怎么就不会从窗户滚蛋呢
Why do you never go out the bloody window?
或许我们不再上床才对
Well, maybe it's best we never got to do it again.
否则那晚就不会感觉特别了
Yeah, it kind of makes that one night special.
理论上来讲  我们还在海外
You know, technically, we still are over international waters.
我去洗手间  待会来找我
I'm going to the bathroom. Maybe I'll see you there in a bit?
太棒了
Okay.
我可以问个问题吗
Hey, can I ask you something?
不行
Uh, no.
我昨晚跟费丽西蒂  一起看《我的巨人》  我心想
Felicity and I, we were watching My Giant. And I was thinking...
自己永远不可能  演得跟那个巨人一样棒
...I'm never gonna be as good an actor as that giant.
你认为我想当演员  是不是只是痴心妄想
Do you think I'm just wasting my life with this acting thing?
不是
No.
那个巨人大概比我小五岁
I mean, the giant's like five years younger than me.
我有办法跟他一样优秀吗
You know, you think I'll ever get there?
会的
Yes.
谢了  没问题
Thanks, man. Okay, man.
但是他比我高好多啊
But what about how much taller he is than me?
我现在已经不可能再长高了
I mean, there's no way I can make myself taller now.
以后科学怎么发展  我不知道
And who knows what science will come up with in the future...
如果我死时  只是一个身高平庸的小人物呢
...but, Chandler, what if I die an unsuccessful, regular-size man?
摩妮卡  你厕所上了半个小时
Hey, Monica. Wow, you've been in the bathroom for, like, a half-hour.
我知道
I know.
你也吃了牛肉
Had the beef tips, huh?
嗨
Hey.
你吃过肉了
You ate meat!
你跟人嘿咻
You had sex!
我们才没有   我知道你没有
No, we didn't. I know you didn't.
我说的是摩妮卡
I was talking about Monica.
菲比  我才没跟人嘿咻
Phoebe, I did not have sex.
怀孕害的我灵感不准
Oh, this pregnancy is throwing me all off.
我要去跟小鸡小鸭打招呼  我跟你去
I'm gonna say hi to the chick and duck. Oh, me too.
你何必去  你不是四天都去喂他们
Why would you need to say hi? You've been feeding them for four days.
没错  我回家好了
Oh, right. Maybe I'll just go home.
只剩下我们两个
Well, we certainly are alone.
幸好我们说好回纽约就不做的
Yes! Good thing we have that "not New York" rule.
没错
Right.
既然你说到这个
Um, listen, since we're on that subject...
我想告诉你
...um, I just wanted to tell you that, um...
当时我在伦敦心情很不好
Well, I was going through a really hard time in London...
因为哥哥结婚  别人还把我认作他妈
...what with my brother getting married and that guy thinking I was Ross' mother.
我知道
Right.
总而言之
Well, anyway, I just...
那晚对我来说意义非凡  我的意思是  我要谢谢你
That night meant a lot to me. And I guess I'm trying to say thanks.
这样
Oh.
我那天也不是随便上床
You know, that night meant a lot to me too.
并不是因为我心情不好
And it wasn't because I was in a bad place or anything.
我很重视那晚是因为  你很性感
It just meant a lot to me because you're really hot.
这样说可以吗  没关系
Is that okay? Ha, ha. That's okay.
而且我也很帅
And I'm cute too?
而且你也很帅  谢谢
And you're cute too. Thank you.
我要去整理行李了  好
All right, I got to go unpack. Okay.
再见
Bye.
我时差还没调回来  这表示我还在伦敦吧
I'm still on London time. Does that count?
没错  太好了
Oh, that counts. Oh, good.
（航厦及出境航班）
瑞秋
Rach.
嗨
Rach. Hi.
你怎么会在这里
What are you doing here?
我在等候补机位回纽约
Well, I've been on standby for a flight home for hours.
你还没等到艾蜜莉
Oh. Oh. So no sign of Emily, huh?
还没
Not yet.
那么
So, um...
你是几点的飞机
What time are you supposed to leave?
最后一次呼叫  前往雅典的1066班机
This is the last call for Flight 1066 to Athens.
最后一次呼叫
The last call.
就快了
Pretty soon, I guess.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我不明白她怎么可以这么做
I just... I don't understand. I mean, how could she do this?
我是不是白痴
What, am I like a complete idiot...
竟然以为她会来
...for thinking she'd actually show up?
不是
No.
你不是白痴   罗斯
You're not an idiot, Ross.
你只是爱得无可救药
You're a guy very much in love.
那还不是一样
Same difference.
搭乘1066班机  前往雅典的旅客请登机
All passengers for Flight 1066 to Athens should now be onboard.
听到了
I get it!
没戏了
Well, that's that.
不  你知道什么啊
No, you know what?
你应该去
I think you should go.
什么  对  我认为你应该
What? Yeah, I do think you should go...
自己去  到遥远的地方
...by yourself. Get some distance.
想个清楚  这对你一定有好处
Clear your head. I think it would be really good.
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
罗斯  你应该要去
Oh, come on, Ross. I think it would be really good for you.
没错  我应该去
I could. I could do that.
对
Yeah.
她实在太扯了
I can't even believe her.
知道吗  我决定去了
You know what? I am going to go.
很好  为什么不呢
Good. Why not?
对不对  没错  没错
Right? Right. Right.
谢了  我们纽约见了
Thanks. Okay, I'll see you back at home.
希望我搭得上飞机
If I ever get a flight out of here.
其实
Hey, well...
算了  怎么了  等等
No. What? Wait, what?
不如你也一起来
Why don't you come?
反正我有两张机票
I mean, I have two tickets. Why not?
不太好吧  真的吗
Well, I don't know, Ross. Really?
是啊  一定很好玩
Yeah, yeah. It'd be great. I mean, you can...
你可以躺在海滩上
You can lay on the beach...
我可以哭诉婚姻失败
...and I can cry over my failed marriage.
你看我多幽默啊
You see how I make jokes? Uh-huh.
真的
Really. I mean...
我需要有朋友陪我
God, I could use a friend.
好吧  也行
Oh, wow. Okay, maybe.
我可以陪你去
Yes, I can do that.
太好了  是啊
Cool. All right, cool.
我们这就走
Okay, we're going to Greece. Yeah, okay.
我忘了拿外套
Aah, aah. I forgot my jacket.
你叫他们等下  好
Well, you tell them to wait. Okay.
等下  好
Wait. Wait. Okay.
艾蜜莉
Emily.
不是啦
Oh, no, no, no.
别走
No! No!
艾蜜莉
Emily!
我要梅洛红酒
Ah, yes. I will have a glass of the Merlot...
这位要气泡白酒
...and he will have a white-wine spritzer.
你们看  机场在动
Hey, look at that. The airport's moving.
飞机在动吗
Hey, are we moving?
飞机在动吗  为什么
Are we moving? Why are we moving?
他们
They... Um...
机长知道飞机在动吗
Yeah, does the captain know that we're moving?
天啊  老天爷
Oh, my gosh.